Benjamin Smith Barton Papers 1789-1815 Mss.B.B284d
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Correspondence, 1783-1817 (Box 1-6)
  - Linnean Society of America, 1803; see oversized
    See Oversized.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803; Broadside, 1p.
      see oversized.
  - Linnean Society of Philadelphia, 1809 May 18; 1 item
    Request for observations on natural history, plants, or minerals.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, TMsSCy, 2p.
  - Lockhead, William, d.1815, 1813 August; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Lohra, Peter, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Luck, John, 1814 July 05; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
  - Macauley, A., 1808 December 28; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Mace, J., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Mackenzie, Colin, 1811 May 10; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      About a missing Mr. Bishop who'd received a letter of introduction from Mackenzie to Barton.
  - Maclean, Mr., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      Regarding the arrival of a box from Dover.
  - Maclure, William, 1815 September 30; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
      Regarding Barton's shipping order.
  - MacNeven, Philip, 1815 November 03-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
      About transporting materials for Dr. Cox.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ANS, 1p.
      Note that he'd safely received the books.
  - Madison, Dr., 1805 May 22-1805 May 25; 2 items
    Regarding a John Clayton.
    - to his son, 1805 May 22; AN, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 May 25; ALS, 2p.
  - Madison, James, 1751-1836, 1809 September 17; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 September 09; ALS, 1p.
  - Marquand, Eleanor C., 2 items
    - Notes on John Bartram, n.d.; TMs, 3p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, n.d.; ALS, 2p.
      About the Bartram bio.+
  - Martin, Alexander, 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Martin, James, 1805 February 23; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Mason, John, 1803; 1 item
    Some few Observations on the Aurora borealis.
    - to The President and Members of the A.P.S., ALS, 1p.
  - Massie, Nathaniel, 1763-1813, 1809 April 20; 1 item
    About an Indian Fort.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Maxwell, H., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, Fragment of ALS, 1p.
      About paper measurements.
  - Mayo, Robert, 1784-1864, 1803 December 22-1806 Dec. 22; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1803 May 10; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 December 22; ALS, 1p.
  - McGhee, S., 1813 June 10; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      In response to Barton's request for the skeleton of a "buffaloe's head."
  - McGillivray, Alexander, 1792 July 29; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - McKell, P., 1806 January 18-1806 Jan. 20; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton to the Managers of the Alms-house, 1806 January 20; ANS, 1p.
      Regarding his attendance.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806; ANS, 1p.
      Asking that Barton to present his bill for attendance at the Alms house.
  - McMahon, Bernard, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
      Inviting Barton to Mr. Hay's Tavern for a meeting.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; AMsS, 1p.
      Notes on fish
  - McMurtrie, Henry, 1815 February 17; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - McNarry, Boyd, 1814 June 1; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Medical Society of Edinburgh, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, PrDS, 1 large page
      Broadside with a series of signatures.
  - Medical Society of London, 1808 December 08; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, DS, 1p.
      Acknowledgement of Barton's natural history discourse.
  - Meerman, F.W., 1807 June 07; 1 item
    - On the Geology of Maryland, AMsS, 7p.
      In German.
  - Memminger, Thomas, 1810 December 03; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Merry, James, 1807 November 3; 1 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 4p.
  - Merry, Samuel, 1814 October 10; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Mettauer, John Peter, 1787-1875, 1809 July 31; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Miller, Dr., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      Description of the composition of volcanic dust.
  - Miller, Christopher, 1797 June; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, AMsS, 1p.
  - Miller, Edward, 1760-1812, 1804 October 06; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Milne, Edmond, 1808 February 22; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Mitchell, E. T., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Mitchell, George, 1809 November 1; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Mitchell, John S., 1806 November 30-1813 Oct. 21; 3 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 October 08; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 November 30; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 December 20; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton or Thomas C. James, 1813 October 21; ALS, 1p.
  - Monroe, James, 1758-1831, 1814 November 08-n.d.; 2 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 November 08; ALS, 1p.
      Requesting a commission
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton to C.J. Ingersol, 1814 November 08; AL, 1p.
      Repeating his request for a commission.
    - from James Monroe, Dept. of State, to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ADS, 1p.
  - Morgan, George, 1743-1810, 1789 August; 1 item
    - to John Morgan, ALS, 3p.
  - Morris, J., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
      Morris vehemently denies contributing to injurious pieces written about Barton.
  - Morris, William, 1806 June 23-1809 July 28; 8 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 June 23; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 August 05; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 November 24; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 February 20; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 April 19; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 April 29; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 May 06; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 July 28; ALS, 1p.
  - Mosby, L. W., 1814 March 1; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
  - Muhlenberg, Gotthilf Henry Ernest, 1782-1844, 1794 February 23-1810 Nov. 1; 3 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1794 February 23; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 August 29; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 November 1; ALS, 2p.
  - Muller, ?, 1805 October 27; 1 item
    About plant specimans and a request for the bones of a beaver's head preserved in whiskey or rum.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Museum d'histoire naturelle (France) (signed Thouin, Andre), 1815 September 28; 1 item
    Reccomendation, in French, for a book on architecture.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ADS, 1p.
  - Neblett, Sterling, 1814 December 1; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 3p.
      Indignant letter about being denied entrance to Barton's lecture.
  - New Hampshire Medical Society, 1810 June 1-1810 Aug. 7; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton signed by L. Spalding, Secretary, 1810 June 1; TMsS, 1p.
      Certificate stating Barton's election as honorary Fellow in the New Hampshire Medical Society.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton signed by L. Spalding, Secretary, 1810 August 07; ALS, 1p.
      Letter informing Barton that he was unanimously elected an honorary Fellow of ;the New Hampshire Medical Society
  - Newcomb, Daniel, 1807 May 11-1807 Nov. 9; 2 items
    Newcomb's letter is about science-related publications. Barton's note is about a new class.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 May 11; ALS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 November 09; ANS, 1p.
  - Norcom, James, 1808 April 20; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Notebook on Electricity, n.d.; 1 item
    Chronicle of electrical experiments. Beautifully written which may indicate that the document was not authored by Barton.
    - by unknown, Ams, 15p.
  - Nourse, Joseph, 1754-1841, 1804 May 23; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Nuttall, Thomas, 1786-1859, n.d.; 10 items
    - Directions to Mr. Thomas Nutall
      All of the items appear to be expedition-related. For a detailed analysis of these notes, see Pennell, Francis. Pennell, a curator at The Academy of Natural Sciences, provided a great many details for Mrs. John R. Delafield from whom he borrowed Barton's papers from in 1936.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 June 16; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 August 10; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 October 10; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 April 22; ALS, 3p.
  - O'Harrah, Sarah, 1814 December 12; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Oliver, Daniel, 1787-1842, 1811 May 20; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Oswald, ?, n.d.; 1 item
    Congratulating Barton's on Jefferson's presidential election.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Pahlen, J. Count, 1811 July 31; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Parkam, Robert G., 1814 May 03; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Parke, Mr., n.d.; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
  - Parrish, Joseph, 1779-1840, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
      Regarding a log-related affliction.
  - Paschall, A., 1812 August 13-n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 August 13; ALS, 1p.
      Asking for Barton's advice on how to treat his boils and finger injury.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; AN, 1p.
      Barton's notes on planets named by the Indians.
  - Paschall, J., 1810 October 04; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 October 04; ALS, 1p.
      About not being able to suppy Barton with hay.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 October 04; AN, 1p.
      Written on the reverse side but obviously unrelated is Barton's notes on venereal disease.
  - Paterson, Samuel, 1808 June 11-1811 Sept. 30; 7 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 June 11; ALS, 5p.
      Requesting that Barton send essays on agriculture in the United States to him in Edinburgh.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 November 21; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 July 17; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 February 12; ANS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1811 September 30; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; fragment of ALS, 4 p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ANS, 1p.
  - Patten, George J., 1810 December 20; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Patterson, D. R., 1808 March 15; 1 item
    Patterson's letter described an illness that he is suffering from and also requested that Barton appraise his marble quarry.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 3p.
  - Patterson, Robert Maskell, 1787-1854, 1809 December 18-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 December 18; ALS, 2p.
      About Barton's portrait.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Patteson, David, 1796 February 03; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827, 1786 July 31; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Rush, ALS, 1p.
      About a "fan chair" drawing that Peale had sent to Rush with the suggestion that it might be presented to the A.P.S. if Rush thought it appropriate.
  - Pearson, George, 1751-1821, 1805 March 04; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Peck, William Dandridge, 1763-1822, 1794 October 06-1813 Jan. 24; 5 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1794 October 06; ALS, 8p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1796 January 27; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1796 March 12; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 September 23; ALS, 2p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1813 January 24; ALS, 2p.
  - Pendergrast, P. E., 1814 July 1-n.d.; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 July 1; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Penington, Edward, 1766-1834, 1809 July 17-1812 Feb. 6; 2 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 July 17; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1812 February 06; ANS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Pennant, Thomas, 1726-1798, 1789 December 22-1794 October 26; 6 items
    General note
    See collection file for transcriptions of sixteen letters to Pennant; presented by George W. Corner, March 1969. Formerly listed as B B248.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition note
    Sixteen manuscript letters to Pennant were purchased from Mrs. S. Manaster ($1500) and accessioned, 05/--/1942. (Aug. 30, 1790; Feb. 24, 1791; Jan. 9, Feb. 27, June 12, 25,Sept.12, Nov.9, Dec. 26,1792; April 7, 24, May 8, 26, June 29, 1793; March 26, April 11,1794).
    - Subscription solicitation for a B.S. Barton publication, 1789 December 22; Broadside, 1p.
      "Proposals for printing, by subscription, an Historical and Philosophical Inquiry into the Original, Nature, and Design of various Remains of Antiquity, which have been discovered in America..."
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1790 August 30
      Phila., A.L.S. 3p. and enc. - Comments on Pennant's British zoology and Arctic zoology offers to communicate materials for new edition. Encloses a prospectus of an Historical and philosophical inquiry into...antiquity, 1789.
      FILM 375 FRAME 1
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1791 February 24
      Phila., A.L.S. 2p. end. and seal. Mutilated. Promises to send material for new edition of Artic zoology. Proposed Pennant for membership in the A.P.S.; shall send Transactions. Expects to continue work on Flora Americana.
      FILM 375 FRAME 2
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1791 February 26
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 January 9; ALS,
      FILM 375 FRAME 3
      Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add. seal. Mutilated. Sends A.P.S. diploma. Material for new edition of Arctic zoology. Pennant's suggestion that Barton undertake a history of fishes.
    - American Philosophical Society, 1792 April 17; TMs Cy, 1p.
      Notice of Committee meeting for "the purpose of collecting and communicating" materials for the composition of a natural history of the "HESSIAN-FLY..."
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 June 12
      A.L.S. 2p. and add. Regrets that his promised communications has caused delay in publication in Arctic zoology. Sends specimens of birds called by the Cherokee Indians- Onacloneita. A.P.S. Transactions.
      FILM 375 FRAME 6
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 June 25
      Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add. More about the Onacloneita. Labors on his work on the Americans and his Flora of the U.S. Corrections for Arctic zoology.
      FILM 375 FRAME 7
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 September 12
      Phila., A.L.S. 9p. and add. seal Lists items sent to Pennant. Theories regarding resemblance of American Indians to Jews, Welsh, Scots,etc. Maps of Pennsylvania and other places in America. Information in re rivers and coal in Pa. and Va.
      FILM 375 FRAME 8
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 November 9
      Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add. Items sent to Pennant. New edition of Arctic zoology. Has received encouragement on his work on Antiquities. Note: answered Jany 31, 1793.
      FILM 375 FRAME 9
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792 Dec. 26
      Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Mutilated. Encloses additional remarks on animals.
      FILM 375 FRAME 10
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1792; ALS, 2p.
      About the severe weather and its affect on the birds.
    - An Account... Means of Preventing the Deleterious Consequences of the Bite..., 1792; TMs Cy, 19p.
      A Barton publication on the "Crotalus Horridus or Rattle-Snake."
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 April 7; ALS, 3p.
      Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add. Mutilated. Flattered that his opinion of the Welsh Indians amused Dr. Pennant. Political observations on France, England and America, "the empire of rational liberty." Permits him to make copy of drawing by William Bartram.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 April 24; ALS, 1p.
      FILM 375 FRAME 12
      Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces bearer, Mr. Robert Leslie, who expects to settle in London. Desires to see Gainsborough's painting of Pennant. Requesting an "anatomical history of the Trichecus manatus of Linnaeus."
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 May 08; ALS, 1p.
      FILM 375 FRAME 13
      Phila., A.L.S. 1p. and add. Introduces bearer, Dr. E[noch ?] Edwards, a member of the Pennsylvania State Legislature. Informing Pennant that he'd sent drawings in care of "a Mr. R. Leslie."
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 May 26; ALS, 2p.
      FILM 375 FRAME 14
      Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add. Exchanging ideas about fish and natural history. Introduces bearer, Joseph Barnes, friend of late James Rumsey. Sends drawing of a bird mentioned by Catesby and [Wm.] Bartram. Desires information on progress made by Gmelin on Systema naturae.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1793 June 29; ALS, 3p.
      FILM 375 FRAME 15
      Phila., A.L.S. 3p. and add. and enc. - [2]71[1]p. Sends manuscripts and drawings for his new edition of Arctic zoology. Bones of the mammoth; advancement of natural history. Sends A.P.S. diploma to be forwarded to Dr. Pallas. Enclosure: Notes on the animals of North America by Doctor B.Sm. Barton... (taken in large part from his Commonplace book...)
    - Notes on the Animals of North America by Doctor B. Sm. Barton..., 1793; AMsS, 75p.
      Scope and Contens note
      A.D. [2]71[1]p. (see with B.S.Barton to T. Pennant); Contains also few notes on birds and fish. Filed with letter of June 29, 1793.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1794 March 26; ALS, 4 p.; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815
      Phila., A.L.S. 3p. and add. Epidemic of yellow fever during 1793. Desires return of drawings, especially that by Wm. Bartram. Has decided to undertake a history of fish along the lines of Pennant's Arctic zoology. Fears that inter course between Britain and U.S. will be less frequent; the embargo.
      FILM 375 FRAME 16
      Existence and Location of Copies note
      Transcript, presented by Dr. Corner, filed with correspondence (Transcript No. 16)
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1794 April 11; ALS, 4 p.; Barton, Benjamin Smith, 1766-1815
      Phila., A.L.S. 3p. and add. Seal Yellow fever epidemic of 1793. Answers his queries relative to natural history, etc., of Pennsylvania. The embargo.
      FILM 375 FRAME 17
      Transcript (2 copies), presented by Dr. Corner, filed with correspondence (Transcript No. 17)
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1794 October 26
      Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and add. (see B.S.Barton Papers) Barton's work on the elk. Offers to be of assistance in Pennant's account of North America.
      Presented by Orion Booksellers, Nov. 1952.
  - Pennell, Francis Whittier, 1886-?, 1941 December 30-1942 Feb. 16; 7 items
    The letters from Francis Pennell to Mrs. John R. Delafield pertain to his request and subsequent use of Delafield's Barton papers in an exhibit at the A.P.S.
    - Article from Bartonia: "The Elder Barton-- His Plant Collection and the...", 1925-1926; TMsCy, 17p.
      Reprinted, No. 9
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1936 July 29; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1936 July 3; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1936 August 27; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1936 September 11; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1936 September 15; TLS, 2p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1936 October 23; TLS, 2p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1936 December 18; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1937 January 07; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1941 December 30; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1942 January 08; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1942 January 13; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1942 January 16; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1942 January 20; TLS, 1p.
    - to Mrs. John R. Delafield, 1942 February 16; TLS, 1p.
    - List of items from Barton collection used in exhibit, n.d.; TMs, 2p.
  - Penshaw, William, n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Perkins, John D., 1 item
    - to John L. Dorsey, ALS, 2p.
      About graduation requirements.
  - Persoon, Christian Hendrick, ?-1836, 1811 July 26; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Peters, Judge, 1809 May 31-1809 Dec. 19; 3 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 May 31; ALS, 3p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 December 19; ALS, 3p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
  - Peters, Richard, 1808 August 12-1810 May 18; 2 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 August 12; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 May 18; ALS, 1p.
  - Pettigrew, John, 1811 October 22; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Pettigrew, Thomas Joseph, 1791-1865, 1815 August 11; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Philadelphia Medical Society, 1815 January 17; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ANS, 1p.
      Request that Barton invite his class to an oration at the Society.
  - Physick, Philip Syng, 1768-1837, 1809 January 1-1809 Jan. 19; 2 items
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 January 1; AN, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 January 19; ALS, 1p.
  - Picton, Thomas, 1805 May 13-1814 Dec. 6; 3 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1805 May 13; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1806 June 1; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1814 December 06; ALS, 3p.
  - Pierson, Charles E., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Pitts, George R., 1814 January 30; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Pollok, Mr., n.d.; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, AN, 1p.
      Dinner invitation
  - Pope, John H., 1808 March 21-n.d.; 3 items
    Regarding Pope's illness and leave of absence from the university.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 March 21; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, n.d.; ALS, 2p.
  - Porter, Andrew, 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Potter, Nathaniel, 1770-1843, 1804 December 13-1808 Oct. 29; 2 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1804 December 13; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 October 29; ALS, 2p.
  - Prather, Benjamin, 1807 May 13; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Prescot, John Sen, 1813 March 16; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Preston, Samuel, 1775?-, 1808 January 30-1810 Sept. 20; 4 items
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 January 30; ALS, 4p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 June 27; ALS, 7p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1809 April 06; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1810 September 20; ALS, 4p.
  - Price, Samuel, 1815 September 30; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804, 1783 September 05; 1 item
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 1p.
  - Prioleau, Thomas Grimball, 1786-1876, 1808 June 11; 1 item
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, ALS, 2p.
  - Pursh, Frederick, 1774-1820, 1806; 1 item
    Botany catalogue.
    - Catalogus plantarum, Ams, 28p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 January 08; ALS, 3p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 May 26; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 July 17; ALS, 3p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 September 09; ALS, 2p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1807 September 14; ALS, 3p.
    - Memorandum of Expenses on the Journey in 1807, AMsS, 3p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 February 22; AMsS, 1p.
    - from Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 March 08; ALS, 1p.
    - to Benjamin Smith Barton, 1808 March 10; ALS, 2p.